PROFILE SUMMARY

A dedicated professional with six years of experience in software development, specializing in iOS applications. I excel in team collaboration, problem-solving, and effective communication because I have strong leadership and interpersonal skills. My experience includes successfully managing projects and fostering a collaborative work environment.

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Certificate in Mobile Application Development Sudbury, Canada Cambrian College

Bachelors in Computer Science & Engineering, Bhaddal, India, IET

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Programming Languages	:	Python, Swift
Micro Services	:	Docker
Tools	:	SourceTree, Figma, Jira, TeamGantt, Trello, Confluence,
Visualization&	:	Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics
Computational Tools		
iOS Skills	:	REST API, SOAP API, GraphQL, Sockets, UIKit, GIT, FastLane, Firebase, CI/CD, Google Analytics, GCD, A/B testing, Mixpanel, Intercom, HealthKit, XCTests, RxSwift, Combine, SwiftUI, Realm, SPM, CocoaPods, CoreLocation, CoreData, CoreAnimation
Design Pattern	:	MVC, MVVM, VIPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer

ICICI Bank

05/2023 - Present

- Gathered client requirements for source data patterns and expected outcomes, making informed decisions on the most suitable patterns. Communicated chosen patterns to clients, outlined necessary changes, and provided guidance on data ingestion processes.
- Constructed a comprehensive Hadoop pipeline for migrating on-premises data to Google Cloud and BigQuery, incorporating both batch and near real-time processes.

Big Data Engineer

Shoppers Drug Mart

11/2022 - 03/2023

- Gathered and interpreted client requirements for source data patterns and outcomes, making informed decisions on suitable patterns and providing expert guidance on data ingestion.
- Monitored and optimized data storage and processing for high performance and costeffectiveness.

Senior Software Engineer

EROUTE TECHNOLOGIES (OmniCard)

05/2021 - 10/2021

• Implemented MixPanel to collect user data for analyzing in-app experience, resulting in a 30% increase in data efficiency and informed decision-making for improved user satisfaction.

- Standardized Git workflows and implemented code review policies that increased code quality and reduced bugs by 25%.
 - https://apps.apple.com/in/app/omnicard/id1569978342

Software Developer

NILE TECHNOLOGIES 11/2020 – 05/2021

- Implemented Google Analytics with AB Testing, optimising user experience via dynamic updates to texts, colour schemes and other elements to achieve 20% higher user engagement.
- Achieved 15% higher app store acceptance rate by following Apple's Human Interface Guidelines.

Software Developer

GYMHOP TECHNOLOGIES

02/2019 - 12/2020

- Implemented JWPlayer to enable video streaming instead of building the system from scratch, reducing the development time by 40 days.
- Successfully managed the app store approval process for multiple app submissions, ensuring a high acceptance rate of 95% and minimizing rejections.
- https://apps.apple.com/lu/app/p5m/id1337646892
- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/p5m-business/id1505816398

Senior iOS Developer

WEBMAAZIX SOLUTIONS

08/2018 - 01/2019

- Resolved battery drainage issues by optimizing location update frequency logic, resulting in a 20% increase in device battery life.
- Reviewed client requirements, wireframes and designs for technical feasibility, ensuring a 95% approval rate.

Senior Software Developer

ETELLIGENS TECHNOLOGIES

08/2017 - 05/2018

- Mentored iOS and Android interns, achieving a 90% program completion rate. Earned a 95% positive feedback rating for effective support and skill development.
- Achieved a 90% user story completion rate, facilitating timely delivery of high-quality applications that met client expectations.

iOS Developer

IGNIVA INFOTECH 09/2015 – 04/2017

- Developed a seamless feature combining pedometer and location updates for accurate step tracking during walking/running, achieving less than 5 steps deviation per 150 recorded, ensuring precise monitoring.
- Upgraded multiple apps from MVC to MVVM design pattern, resulting in 30% reduced code complexity and improved maintainability and testability.